<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nafeem Haque</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nafeem Haque</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>haquenafeem.github.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 12:58:57 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Publish Go Package</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-publish-go-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 12:58:57 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-publish-go-package/</guid>
      <description>All the developers that love golang, has one point in time thought about releasing his own golang package. In this blog we are going to describe step by step process on how to publish your go package.
Basic Requirements Your code needs to be in a public repository. Your repository should have a LICENSE file [Ex MIT,APACHE&amp;hellip;.]. You need to create tags with format of vX.X.X and push. run git tag v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Unit Test in Go</title>
      <link>/posts/writing-unit-test-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 09:56:15 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/writing-unit-test-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Writing unit tests in golang is very easy. In this post we are going to create a simple function called Add. and then write unit test for that function. We are going to use golang&amp;rsquo;s in built test package. Lets go ahead and start.
At first create a directory where you wanna put your codes Initialize go module, I have done as such go mod init calc , but the convention is go mod init github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Webcam Feed Using Python OpenCV</title>
      <link>/posts/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 11:44:29 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post-3/</guid>
      <description>Reading webcam feed is very easy using python. We are going to introduce reading webcam using opencv in this post. We will explore more about opencv on later posts.
Lets jump right into the task.
First you are going to need to install opencv in your environment/virtual environment. we are going to run pip install opencv-python to fetch the dependency.
Now follow the steps as mentioned:
Create a python file, I will use main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gin-Gonic : Rest API implementation for a `todo` resource</title>
      <link>/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 19:53:59 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>Initial Steps First create a directory Go to that directory Initialize with &amp;lsquo;go mod init todoapp&amp;rsquo;, usually it is a good practice to initialize with something like github.com/{username}/{reponame} Run go get -u github.com/gin-gonic/gin from cli now let&amp;rsquo;s create an empty main.go file, and have the basic code like this:
package main import ( &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; ) func main() { fmt.Println(&amp;#34;hello,world!&amp;#34;) } if you run this program by go run main.go you will get the following output:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging Two Maps In Golang</title>
      <link>/posts/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post-1/</guid>
      <description>Map is a built in data structure provided by golang. It is used to store key,value pairs. You can use maps for different purposes and therefore it is important to know features and tricks to deal with maps. Today we will take a look at how we can merge two different maps into one.
There could be multiple ways to merge maps including using third party libraries. but lets look at two ways we can achieve this by using just the language itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
